# **CHEN SHUYANG**

M: 97835928 | E: <a href="mailto:chenshuyangbusiness@gmail.com">chenshuyang2003</a>

## **PROFILE**

Singapore Polytechnic Diploma in Information Technology Undergraduate with experience in leading and organizing team discussions for school projects and FYP. Acting as a flexible, adaptable, and efficient team player. A great learner who works with a strong sense of urgency and thieves for the best quality work in a fast-paced setting.

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## SP Forums (Login Accounts) | May 2021 - Nov 2021

- Developed a Forum website for students to have discussions of school related things
- Post questions for others to discuss answers by commenting below the question
- Users are able to save questions, like questions or comments posted by others
- Search questions they have in mind through keywords.
- Project management tools and frameworks were also used to mange the team and project

## Payment Reminder App (UI Design) | Nov 2020 - Feb 2021

Design user interface for the best user experience

#### <u>SP Hawkers</u> | Nov 2020 - Feb 2021

- Allow users to view food products and its details that are available.
- Allow add-to-cart and make purchases
- Admin is able to do inventory and user management
- Coded with JAVA and MySQL

## MyMentalHealth | May 2021 - Nov 2021

- Mobile application that allows users to track emotions through a diary and listening to meditation tracks.
- Includes great UI for better user experience
- Coded with JAVA and within android studio

## Amazon Web Services Report | May 2021 - Aug 2021

- Deploying an application on AWS while learning some AWS features
- Recording the steps in a report

## Web Application Security Assessment | Apr 2021 - Jun 2021

- Make use of several vulnerability test to check for any bugs within a website
- Provided Suggestions to prevent those bugs and written in a report

## Project Management (Scrum) | Apr 2021 - Aug 2021

- Use scrum framework to complete a project
- Made use of product backlogs, use cases diagrams, and many more tools to scope out the project and complete it.

## FrontEnd Designing | Nov 2021 - Mar 2022

- TravelWithSP https://travellingwithsp.herokuapp.com/
- SP Store <a href="https://spstorecollection.herokuapp.com/">https://spstorecollection.herokuapp.com/</a>

#### **EDUCATION & SKILL**

GCE Ordinary Level Qualification, HaiSing Catholic School | Jan 2016 - Dec 2019 Diploma in Information Technology, Singapore Polytechnic | Apr 2020 - Feb 2023 IT Skills: JAVA, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS, Git, ReactJS, Android Studio, Eclipse, Microsoft SQL server, Data Engineering, Data analysis with excel, Figma, ExpressJS, Bootstrap

#### **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

Project Management - Managed school projects like FYP using scrum framework.

Creative - Provided Ideas on UI and features during school projects.

Efficiency - Completes my work before deadlines with high quality.

Problem solving - Independent thinking and solving of bugs in school projects

Teamwork - Organises and collaborates with teammates to complete school projects

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Panasonic Industrial Devices Singapore, Bedok | March 2021 - April 2021

Helped to operate machines, quality check, and packing of product parts

#### Redmart Ltd, Jalan Buroh | Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

Pick food items from the warehouse and pack it into tote boxes for delivery

## Shopee Express, Punggol | Aug 2021 - Nov 2021

• Deliver parcels shoppers purchased on shoppee and send them to their homes.

#### Grab Food, Pasir Ris | Mar 2022 - Present

• Pick up food items from restaurants and deliver them to the customer using a bike

#### OBS Financial Solutions Pte Ltd. Vision Exchange | Sep 2022 - Feb 2023

- Develop product modules such as MM, MFUND, BOND, etc.
- Develop Standalone JAVA, NODEJS, ReactJS applications for internal use
- Debugging of errors in their application and report writing
- Unit testing and reporting